robhunter

software engineering professional

Self-motivated, highly adaptable, and organized software engineering professional with eight years of experience specializing in automated build and test systems. Outstanding troubleshooting and problem solving skills, with a proven ability to identify and solve root-cause issues.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Commercialization Engineering Process Lead

Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

Nov 2010 - Present - Waterloo, ON

- * Currently employed in this position
- Incorporated agile development and testing into new development projects;
 piloting Scrum, TDD, usability testing, and UI test automation
- Refactored installers and tests to be automatable, achieving 100% build and 70% UI test automation to reduce release testing cycles to under a week
- Owner for components shared across product portfolio including license protection controls, automatic update notification, application analytics

QA/QC Coordinator for Water Services Software Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

Apr 2008 - Nov 2010 - Waterloo, ON

- Managed QA/QC team, and initiated co-op student recruitment
- Managed technical support team and handled escalated client installation, deployment, and licensing issues
- Introduced continuous integration systems and improved build performance
- Refactored installation packages to improve installation user experience
- Led a project to replace the licensing protection across all software products developed in Waterloo, developed the original design and prototypes, and managed the development and integration
- Managed an out-sourced project to deploy multiple software applications in a streamlined manner through a chained installation

Software Build and Deployment Specialist Schlumberger Canada Limited (Schlumberger Water Services)

May 2006 - Apr 2008 - Waterloo, ON

- Responsible for the release of all software products
- Updated release processes to include trade compliance procedures, license auditing, and review of EULA
- Restructured the source control configuration to improve branching
- Performed all independent builds of water services software products
- Introduced automation into the software build process

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo, Canada

B.ASc. Computer Engineering (Co-op), 2006

CO-OP WORK EXPERIENCE

Control Systems Software Developer ATS Automation Tooling Systems Inc.

2005 (8 months) - Cambridge, ON

Machine vision software development in C++/C

Payload Assistant
Canadian Space Agency

2004 (4 months) - St. Hubert, QC

 Canadian telemetry project for International Space Station in C++/VB.NET

Assistant Building Systems Engineer Dufferin-Peel Catholic District School Board

2003 (4 months) - Mississauga, ON

- Automated backup of HVAC control programs using C++/Win32 API
- Warehouse database project in FileMaker Pro

Software Developer

Synexus Global Inc.

2002/2003 (8 months) – Niagara Falls, ON

 Hydroelectric power generation decision support software development in C++

CONTACT

rphunter@gmail.com

http://www.linkedin.com/in/rphunter